很久很久以前 确切时间是1870年
Once upon a time, 1870 to be exact,
有一个十六岁的男孩
a 16-year-old kid
从苏格兰的寒冷之处而来
travelled from the cold shoulder of Scotland
一路前往美国的炎热之地
to the baking heart of America
寻找他的爱人 他的名字叫做杰伊
to find his love. His name was Jay.
而她的名字叫做罗塞
Her name was Rose.
飞马座
Pegasus...
大熊座
The great bear...
天龙座
The dragon...
仙女座
Andromeda...
猎户腰带[指横贯该座腰部的3颗亮星]
Orion's belt.
西部 慢调
我一路向西
I was drifting west
在科罗拉多州的深处
when I picked up his trail
我发现了他的踪迹
deep in Colorado territory.
羊入虎口
A jackrabbit in a den of wolves.
能活着就已经很幸运了
Fortunate to be alive.
手举起来 小子
Arms abroad, boy.
-印第安人还是白人 -额 先生
Red skin or white? Um... sir...
我 我是英国人 苏格兰人
I'm-I'm British... Scottish.
抓住那个野蛮人
Catch the savage.
我是杰伊·卡文迪什
I'm Jay Cavendish...
卡文迪什夫人的儿子
Son of lady Cavendish.
我们都是婊子生的
We're all sons of bitches.
你耍诈 小子
Grave play, boy.
先生 放下你的枪
Sir... lower your pistol.
嘿
Hey.
把枪擦干净 上点油
Clean it, oil it.
你要做什么
What do you want?
他是军官
He was an officer.
虚有其表罢了
Wearing a dress don't make her a lady.
他们不是军人
They ain't soldier.
至少现在不是了
Least no more.
他们是印第安人掠杀者
Injun slayers.
继续一个人向西走的话
Keep headin' west solo,
你是见不到明天的太阳的
you'll be dead by dawn.
你能走到这里已经是奇迹了
How you made it this far is a miracle.
-我自己会照顾自己 -当然了 小子
I take care of myself. Sure, kid.
你需要有人护送 而我就是个护送者
You need chaperoning, and I'm a chaperone.
跟一个杀人犯一起走会更安全吗
Safer to travel with a killer?
是的
That's right.
首先 我们要拯救你这匹小矮马的性命
First let's save your pony's life.
考虑到有一大票混蛋
Counted a dozen of them bastards
在这附近袭击那些印第安人
attacked those Indians back there.
除了他们三个 还有太多了
Minus three... that leaves too many.
《一路向西》
"Ho for the west..."
前往加拿大和美国西北部的
A traveller and emigrant's handbook...
旅行移民指南手册
"...to Canada and the north west states of America"
爱德华·海柏尔·霍尔所著
by Edward Hepple Hall.
向西一路好走啊
Well ho for the west.
钱 现在给我五十美金 到达目的地再给五十美金
Dollars... 50 now, 50 when we split.
到我们抵达银色幽灵森林为止
Until we reach a forest called silver ghost.
上路吧
Let's drift.
-你叫什么名字 -退回去
- What's your name? - Drop back.
成一列纵队
Single file.
你为什么要去西部
Why are you headin' west?
你不想知道我为什么要去西部吗
You care not why I'm headed west?
因为一场事故
There was an accident.
我的女朋友和她父亲逃离了苏格兰
My girl and her father fled from Scotland...
去了西部 都是我的错
Settled out west. It was all my fault.
没懂我的暗示吗 小子
Take a hint, kid?
-我们彼此相爱 -你们当然相爱了 小子
We love each other. Sure you do, kid.
杰伊 一千种死法
Jay! A thousand ways to die...
选一个吧
Choose one.
我选弓箭
Bow and arrow.
傻小子
Silly boy.
轮到我了
My turn.
你喜欢我们的歌曲吗
是的
我非常喜欢这首歌
这是一首关于爱的歌
爱就像死亡那般普遍
那小子是个奇想家
That kid was a wonder.
他看待事情的角度与众不同
He saw things differently.
对他来说 我们生活在一片充满希望和善意的土地上
To him, we were in a land of hope and good will.
而在我眼里
The way I saw it...
这世界充满艰难险阻
Kick over any rock
更像是一个暴徒
and most likely a desperado
只要有一点点利益可图
will crawl out and knife you right in the heart
它就会蠢蠢欲动 一刀一刀切割着你的心脏
if there was a dollar in it.
一样的星星 一样的月亮
Same stars, same moon...
总有一天我们会在月亮上漫步
One day we'll be wanderin' 'round that moon.
人们会建造一条铁路
They'll build a rail road.
一条贯穿天地的铁路
A rail road up and down the ways.
一条直达月亮的铁路
A rail road to the moon.
我们一到那儿
And when we get there...
第一件事就是
The first thing we'll do...
掠杀那些土著人
Is hunt the natives down.
月亮上没有印第安人
No Indians on the moon.
不 是月亮上的土著人
No, the natives of the moon.
月球人
The moon people.
飞马座
Pegasus...
大熊座
The great bear...
-天龙座 -嘘
The dragon... shh.
坐下
Sit down.
这是我最后一次替你收拾烂摊子了
This is the last time I'm gonna clean up your shit.
罗塞经过这里的时候一定是冬天
It must have been winter when Rose passed through here.
她长什么样子的
What's she like?
她很美
She's a beauty.
而且话不多
And she does not waste words.
微言大义 字字珠玑
They tumble out... ...Wit following wisdom.
你没和她睡过 是不是
You haven't bedded her, have you?
抬起尾部
Grab that end.
你真是个禽兽
You're a brute.
前面有家小商店
Trading post up ahead.
我们能坐在餐桌上吃顿饭了
We can dine at a table while sittin' on a chair.
把马栓在后面
Tie the horses 'round back.
杀人犯
约翰  罗斯
罗塞  罗斯
所有人都知道赏金的事
Everyone knew about the bounty...
以及他的女儿
罗塞·罗斯
赏金 2000 美金
不论生死
除了杰伊
Except Jay.
罗塞  罗斯
而他正带我向赏金前进
He was leading me right to it.
像我们这样的法外之徒
There were few of us left.
所剩不多
Men beyond the law.
但往往最危险的那个才能笑到最后
But the most dangerous are the last to fall.
能请你先把你的枪放在柜台
May I ask you to place your iron on the counter
再去看吗
while you browse?
我们要在这里吃饭
We'll be dining.
-我能试穿一下这件西服吗 -当然可以 请随意
May I try on a suit? Sure, be my guest.
来点威士忌吗
Whiskey?
-有肉吗 -有些坏了的培根
Got any meat? I got condemned bacon.
用来换子弹的 这两者都能迅速地杀死你
Traded it for bullets. Both'll kill you pretty quick.
-拿条毯子 谢谢 -毯子
-Blanket please. -Blanket?
女士
Ma'am,
打包东西之前你得先付款
you have to purchase items 'fore baggin' 'em.
在美国 我们是这么解决的
How we do it here in America.
约翰
Johan.
抱歉了
Sorry.
-拿钱来 求求你 -你可要看清楚
Money... please. Well now, looky here.
你要知道 如果我给你钱
You realize if I give you money...
这儿可是你唯一可以花钱的地方
Here's the only place around where you can spend it.
约翰
Johan!
钱
Money...
约翰 约翰
Johan... johan!
深呼吸
Breathe.
吸气 吐气
In... and out.
钱
Money.
Money!
深呼吸 吸气
Breathe. In...
-吐气 -给我钱
And out. Money!
深呼吸
Breathe.
钱
Money!
吸气
In...
-吐气 -钱
And out. Money!
拿些必需品走
Grab some provisions.
杰伊
Jay!
该死
Shit.
擦干你的眼泪 小子 我们出发了
Dry your eyes, kid, let's drift.
我们本可以带上他们的
We could have taken them in.
带去哪里
In where?
你觉得
How do you feel...
我怎样
About me?
你就像我从没有过的小弟弟
You're the little brother I never had.
你不是认真的
You don't mean that.
你不是那个意思
That's not what you mean.
对不起 我的罗密欧
I'm sorry, my Romeo...
但“这种狂暴的快乐
But "These violent delights..."
往往预示着狂暴的结局”
Have violent ends."
你的选择是什么
What choice do you have?
农民 还是渔夫
A farmer... A fisherman...
你最好现在就走 杰伊
Best you leave now, Jay.
-躲到床底下去 -不
Under the bed. No.
-爸爸 -罗塞
Daddy. Rose.
长得真快啊
Growin' up quick.
约翰 卡卢姆 罗塞 威利 安格斯
John, Calum, Rose. Willie, Angus.
卡文迪什勋爵 有什么能帮到你的吗
Lord Cavendish, can I help you?
我来找我的侄子的
I've come for my nephew.
你不该来这里的 这些人都是农民
You should not be in here. These people are peasants.
我现在和罗塞在一起
I'm with rose now.
我不是坏人
I come in peace.
我已听见你的颂歌 来 来
My ears hear your music. Come. Come.
来啊 来
Come! Come!
坐
Sit.
我有咖啡
I have coffee.
你是个作家
You a writer?
或许吧
Perhaps.
我在写《纪录
I am "Recording the decline"
土著部落的衰落
of the aboriginal tribes...
他们的风俗 文化和习俗
Their customs, culture and habits...
希望能阻止他们的灭亡
In the hope of preventing their extinction
或是转变为基督教徒》
"Or conversion to christianity."
我作品的名字
The title of my account.
-是不是太长了 -或许吧
Too long? Perhaps.
那么 如今的东部 有什么新消息
So, now. East. What news?
暴力和苦难
Violence and suffering.
西部呢
And west?
梦想
Dreams...
和辛劳
And toil.
我中途经过一个印第安人营地的灰烬残址
I passed through burnt remains of an Indian camp.
真是可怕的消息
This is dreadful news.
一个种族灭绝了
A race extinct...
他们的文化被放逐
Their culture banished,
他们的领土被更名
their places re-named,
此后只有在怀旧之作 神话篇章
only then will they be viewed with selective nostalgia,
以艺术为幌子的浪漫传奇 以及文学作品中
mythologized and romanticized in the safe guise of art...
才能见到他们
And literature.
这是我们的新世界
This is a new world for us...
也是他们的新世界
Also for them.
你一定饿了
You must be hungry.
在此之前 我唯一的同伴是一个禽兽
'Til now, my sole company's been a brute.
很遗憾知道这事
Sorry to hear this.
我逃跑了
I escaped.
谢谢你
Thank you.
昨天 我杀了一个女人
I killed a woman yesterday.
人在江湖身不由己
Part and parcel.
你不介意陪伴一个杀人犯吗
You care not to share your company with a murderer?
我介意的话就只能独来独往了
I'd be a lonely man if I did.
我不是法官
I am no judge...
也不是神父
Nor father.
人生苦短
In a short time...
这些都将成为记忆
This will be a long time ago.
在这儿睡一晚吧
Camp here.
-要毯子吗 -谢谢你
Blanket? Thank you.
我会想出一些良策的
I shall dream up some advice,
到了早上
and in the morning,
用新鲜的鸡蛋做给你
dish it up with fresh eggs.
-你叫什么名字 -韦尔纳
What's your name? Werner.
我是杰伊
I'm Jay.
晚安 还有谢谢你 韦尔纳
Goodnight, and thank you, Werner.
向西
你可以吃那些蘑菇
You can eat those.
多吃点 你就能飞到罗塞身边了
Eat enough of them, you can fly to Rose.
你杀了韦尔纳
You kill Werner?
没有
No.
没有理由杀他
No reason.
这是我所有的钱
This is all the money I have.
把我安全地送到那里
Get me there in one piece.
没问题 小子
Sure, kid.
吃块饼吧
Have a biscuit.
这真是羞耻
That's just a shame.
是吗
Is it?
不
No.
不 这并不羞耻
No, it's not.
查尔斯·达尔文说过物竞天择
Charles Darwin talks of evolution by natural selection.
对我们来说 真希望他是错误的
For our sake, let's hope he's wrong.
刀子一定要非常锋利
Knife's gotta be as sharp as a razor.
你拿着刀子轻触皮肤
You hold the knife flush against the skin.
然后反向地刮
And it's a scraping motion against the grain.
不是用切的
Not a slicing motion.
就像这样
Like so.
这会让你见到她时依然风采迷人
That'll make you presentable for her.
我知道你为什么需要我的帮助
I know why you need my help.
是吗
Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
因为你孤独
You're lonely.
你是一个孤独的人
You're a lonely man.
-没错 小子 -没有错 小子
Sure, kid. Sure, kid.
我们出发吧
Let's drift.
做一个沉默 孤独的流浪者
The silent, lonely drifter.
你是一个非常孤独的人
You're a lonely, lonely man.
不用你操心我 别动
No need to concern over me. Hold still.
我想表达的是
All I'm sayin' is...
除了生存 生活还有更多的意义
There's more to life than just survivin'.
是啊 还有死亡
Yeah, there's dyin'.
生存不只是知道如何剥野兔皮
Survival ain't just how to skin a jackrabbit.
而是还要明白 该吼的时候吼 该静的时候静
It's knowing when to bluster and when to hush.
该挨打的时候挨打
When to take a beating...
该还手时还手
And when to strike.
你的家人呢
Where's your folks?
父亲埋在爱尔兰
Father's in the ground in Ireland,
母亲埋在加拿大
mother's in the ground in Canada.
那你为什么没被埋
So what keeps you from joining 'em?
我不知道 小子 不要再问我这些鬼问题了
I don't know, kid. Quit askin' me shit.
-你出现前 我一直过得挺好  -我出现
-I was fine 'til you showed up. -I showed up?
是你出现了
You showed up.
是啊 或许我已经厌倦出现了
Yeah, well maybe I'm tired of showin' up.
刮完了
You're done.
我能过来吗
May I enter?
这里是自由的国度
It's a free country.
我一直都是这么和当地人说的
Try telling the natives that.
我来做买卖 一杯咖啡
I propose a trade, a mug of coffee
换最好的进口苦艾酒
for the finest imported absinthe
和上等的雪茄
and a cigar of unrivaled quality.
我们喝茶
We drink tea.
给你一支 年轻人
One for you, young man.
你还是老样子啊
There's still not a mark on you.
你认识他
You know him?
-去死吧 佩恩 -我试过了
- Fuck yourself, Payne. - I've tried.
相信我 我真的试过了
Believe me, I have tried.
-这咖啡真不错 -那是茶
-Well, that's damn fine coffee. -It's tea.
给你
There you are.
敬生不逢时
To bad times in the green hour.
一口干了 小子 干了才过瘾
Down it, boy! That's liquid joy!
-你们往西走吗 -北
- You headed west? - North.
我往 南走
Yeah, I'm headed... South.
北方太冷 我受不了
Chill, can't stand it, makes my...
冷得我关节疼
Makes my joints ache.
为什么往北走 小子 有特别的人在北方吗
So why north, kid? Someone special?
是你的小心肝吗
Your sweetheart, maybe?
我逗你玩儿呢 逗你的
I'm teasing, I'm teasing. I'm teasing.
你一定是星期天出生的 是星期天吗
You must be born on a Sunday? You born on a Sunday?
-是吗 星期天出生的 -我不知道
-Yeah? You born on a Sunday? -Don't know.
这么说来 你们往北走真是幸运
So, it's fortunate that you're, headed north
因为西方不好 有大麻烦
'cause west... it's bad, it's big trouble.
暴风雨要来了
Big storm coming.
别吓唬他 佩恩 他还是个小孩子
Easy, Payne. He's just a kid.
不 他不是 他也是个亡命之徒 和我们一样
No, he's not. He's an outlaw, just like us.
我们一起喝吧 敬朋友 老朋友和新朋友
Anywho, let's drink. To friends! Old and new.
转起来
Spin it.
还不错嘛
That's pretty good.
把土全都清出来 清干净
Get that dirt, all of it, clean, clean it.
我要去尿尿
I need to piss.
离营地远点儿
Away from camp.
不难看出 你们两个为什么一拍即合
It's easy to see how you two crossed paths.
一个是堕落天使 另一个是明日恶魔
One's a falling angel, the other one's a rising devil.
我不是天使
I ain't no angel...
没错
True.
你以为和他组队
Do you think that's a smart play?
是聪明的把戏吗
Teaming up with him?
比跟踪他要快 要简单
Quicker than tracking him, simpler.
这不是什么把戏
Ain't no play about it.
是啊 我猜如果你知道罗塞和她爸爸在哪儿
Yeah, I guess if you knew where rose and daddy was,
你就不会给这小子当保姆了
you'd be done babysitting.
你从来就不是什么省油的灯 不是吗
Never was a bean-spiller, was ya?
似醉非醉 似醒非醒
Not... sober, nor liquored up, never was.
你能用两千美金干什么呢
What you gonna do with two thousand dollars?
-回来吧 -我和你不一样 佩恩
-Come back to us. -I'm not like you, Payne.
赛拉斯
Silas?
你们对赛拉斯和佩恩做了什么
What have you done with Silas and Payne?
退下 小子 佩恩要留活口
Back down, kid. Payne needs him alive.
你还有机会的
You'll get your chance.
河怎么不见了
What've you done with the river?
他们抢走了
They took it.
-谁抢走了 -没看见他们的脸 -孩子
-Who took it? -Didn't see their face. Kid.
我要说的是
All I'm saying
在我们那个年代 我们都躲悬赏海报远远的
is, in my day, we tried to keep outta the papers.
而你们年轻人却不知天高地厚
You youngsters tryin' to get in 'em makes no sense.
斯盖尔 我要说的是
All I'm sayin', skell,
我希望得到尊重
is I want folks to respect me.
如果没人知道你死了 那死还有什么意义
What's the point in dyin' if nobody knows you're dead?
杀戮也是一个道理
Same goes for killing.
很久以前 我曾和一个年轻人搭档过
I partnered up with a youngling, once upon a time,
他叫比尔·埃里森
by the name of bill Alison.
他非常渴望出名
He was dying to be famous.
应该说 极度渴望出名
Actually, killing to be famous.
一次他来找我说
He come to me one time, and he said...
我杀了三十个人 还有无数野蛮人
I killed 30 men, and countless savages,
竟然还没有悬赏我的海报
and I still ain't got me no wanted poster.
我说 杀人可没有什么正义可言
Where's the justice in that, I said?
所以我想
So I'm thinking
唯一能阻止这小子滥杀无辜的办法
the only way to stop this kid from croakin' more innocents
就是画一张海报 让他看见
is to draw up a poster. Let him find it.
第二天一早
The next morning,
我把海报钉在了他买醉的酒吧外面
I pinned the poster outside the waterin' hole he was drowning in.
他没过多久就看见了
Wasn't long before he sees the poster,
“比尔·埃里森 无论死活 悬赏500美金”
"Bill allson, $500 dead or alive."
-他冲我喊 -斯盖尔
- He yells me over. - Skelly!
他的话让我凉到了骨子里
And what he says chills me to the bone.
他说了什么
What'd he say?
“赏金明天就能涨到1000了”
"Be a thousand by the 'morrow."
第二天一早 我去把海报摘了下来
The next morning, I go to get the poster,
打算钉在另一个小镇
and pin it up in the next town.
海报已经不见了 我听见了一声枪响
The poster ain't there. I hear a gunshot...
和一个人倒地的声音 我转身
And a body hit dirt. Spin around
看见那个狗娘养的混蛋倒在血泊中
to see this mean son of a bitch leaning over a... blob.
我猜是有个混蛋看见了海报
Well, I'm presuming this bastard seen the poster,
以为是真的
thought it real,
随即为了赏金枪杀了他
and gunned down bill for the reward.
于是我走过去 开了枪
So I walk and I shoot,
嘣一声 他跪倒在地 死了
and bang! He falls to his knees and dies.
他就那么跪着 像是在祈祷重生
On his knees, like he's prayin' to be alive again.
当我
As I...
走向那个可怜虫的时候
Walked towards the dear departed,
比尔·埃里森从对面的酒吧走了出来
bill Alison steps out from the saloon across the street.
活得好好的
Alive as you an' I.
一手拿着威士忌
Bottle of whiskey in one hand,
另一手拿着海报
and the wanted poster in the other.
我走向那个祈祷的死人
I step up to the prayin' dead man
用脚踢了他一下
and nudge him with my boot.
他倒下了 面前是一大团皮草和肉
He falls, revealin' a-a dead lump of fur and meat.
那是一只黑熊
It was a goddamned black bear.
你知道比尔·埃里森跟我说什么吗
You know what bill Alison says to me?
他说什么
What'd he say?
他说“你这个嫉妒心强的混蛋
He says, "You jealous bastard",
想有张自己的悬赏海报”
trying to get your own poster."
-放屁 -这个故事不错 斯盖尔
-Bullshit! -That's a good one, skelly.
我想可能这是个天大的误会
Th-there's been an appalling misunderstanding.
我走错了营地
I'm at the wrong camp.
晚安 我走了
Goodnight. Good riddance.
赛拉斯 树丛里有一群人
Silas. There's some people in the woods.
你爱她吗
You love her?
-谁 -罗塞
-Who? -Rose.
-是的 -那就回家吧 小子
-Yes. -Then go home, kid.
她是我的
She's mine.
她不属于任何人
She's nobody's.
-我要向你宣战 -嘘 嘘 嘘
-Fighting talk! -Shhh. Shhh. Shhh. Shhh.
你总是在嘘我
You're always shushing me!
因为你话总是太多
'Cause you're always running your mouth off.
-杰伊小鸟 你为什么这么悲伤 -赛拉斯 赛拉斯
-Jay-bird, why so sad? -Silas! Silas!
赛拉斯
Silas!
赛拉斯 我找不到我的枪了
Silas! I can't find my gun!
帮帮我
Help!
进去吧 小鸟
Come in, kotori.
小鸟
Kotori.
一切又恢复平静了
Turned out nice again.
我要咖啡
Coffee.
你总是要喝咖啡 喝了又吐出来
You always asks for coffee, and you always spits it out.
-我的天啊 -注意你的用语 罗塞
-For God's sake. Language, rose.
略为改进 它就不会洒了
An improvement, it stays on the table.
只有我的嘴是干的
Only thing dry's my mouth.
我头疼死了
My head is killing me.
昨晚的事你一点都不记得了吗
You remember nothing from last night?
我记得佩恩 然后就下大雨了
I remember Payne, then rain.
把绳子给我
Give me that rope.
不赖嘛 小子
Not bad, kid.
当我加入佩恩的团伙时
I must've been Jay's age
我一定只有杰伊这么大
when I joined Payne's gang.
那是我们买卖繁荣的时期
Those were prosperous times in our trade.
当我独自行动时
When I split,
我才有幸活出自己的生活
I was lucky to do so with my life.
哇
Whoa.
他们想干什么
What do they want?
他们是赏金猎人 你知道那是什么意思吗
They're bounty hunters. You know what that means?
他们为钱而来
They hunt bounty.
他们追捕罗塞和她爸爸 还有血液和金钱
They hunt rose, daddy, blood, money.
罗塞  罗斯
-“无论死活” -只有死路一条 小子
- "Wanted dead or alive... " - Dead or dead, kid.
是我把他们引向她的
And I'm leading them to her.
-我们把他们引到南方 -还会有其他人的
-We'll lead them South. -There'll be others.
其他人
Others?
两千美金可是个无法抗拒的诱惑
Two thousand dollars entices a certain breed of undesirable.
你也无法抗拒吗
Just what breed are you?
当地的部落称这片森林为“心灵树之乡”
Local tribes call this forest "The place of spirit trees".
猎人则称之为“银色幽灵”
Trappers call it "Silver ghost".
据传说 这片森林是有去无回的
Legend has it, folks go in, they don't come out.
至少我们能扰乱佩恩团伙的注意力
At least we may shed the superstitious from Payne's company.
去你妈的 赛拉斯
God damn you Silas.
谁啊
Who be it?
维克多·塞尔夫 维克多·塞尔夫牧师
Victor self. Reverend Victor self.
不好意思打扰你了
Sorry to bother you,
我在找一个叫帕克的小伙子
looking for a chap by the name of Parker,
詹姆斯·帕克
James Parker.
这儿没有叫帕克的人 牧师 不进来坐坐吗
No Parkers here, minister. Won't you come in?
感谢您的好意 先生 我就不进去了
Sir, I thank you, but decline.
罗塞
Rose!
抱歉 牧师
I'm sorry, minister.
我要去完成上帝交付的任务了
The good lord has me on an errand.
愿主保佑你
Bless you.
-和你美丽的妻子 -是我的女儿
And your lovely wife. My daughter.
祝你今天愉快 先生
Good day, sir.
上帝在看呢 罗塞
Heavens above, rose.
苏格兰很远 很远
Scotland is far, far away.
没人知道我们在哪儿 没人知道我们是谁
Nobody knows where we are. Nobody knows who we are.
他知道我是你的女儿
He knows I'm your daughter,
我叫罗塞 他知道我们在哪儿
I'm called rose, and he knows we're here.
他是被上天派来的
He was sent by Providence.
上帝感受到了我动摇的信念
The lord sensed my wavering faith.
要下雨了
Rain is coming.
“你不应害怕夜晚的惊骇
"Thou shall not be afraid of any terror of night,"
也不应害怕日间飞驰的箭羽
nor for the arrow that flyeth by day.
或在黑暗中苏醒的瘟疫
For the pestilence that waketh in darkness,
和在正午毁灭的疾病”
"Nor for the sickness that destroyeth in noon day."
“远处恐惧的阴影在摇曳
"O'er all there hung the shadow of fear,"
令幽灵胆怯的神秘
a sense of mystery the spirit daunted,
简单如耳边的轻言
and said as plain as a whisper in the ear,
这片地方不能安眠”
"This place is haunted."
赛拉斯 树在移动
Silas? The trees are moving.
这叫宿醉 小子 你会习惯的
It's called a hangover, kid. You'll get used to it.
接得漂亮
Nice catch.
我路上再给你包扎
I'll fix you up on the way.
我找到了
I've made it.
你确定那是他们
You sure that's them?
和我想象中的一模一样
Exactly what I imagined.
嘿 赛拉斯 塞 赛拉斯
Hey. Silas! S-Silas!
赛拉斯 你干什么 住手 不要
Silas, what are you doing? Stop! No!
赛拉斯 赛拉斯
Silas, Silas!
下手快点
Do it quick.
我不会杀你的
I ain't gonna kill you.
我是在保你的小命 我们都没有枪
I'm keeping you alive. We don't have a gun between us.
别动 这是什么
Hold still. What is this?
帮你防晒
It stops the sun burning you up.
我死都要保护罗塞
I'll protect rose or die trying!
这就是我所害怕的
That's what I'm afraid of.
你敢碰她一下 我就杀了你
Lay a finger on her, and I'll kill you!
爸爸
Dada!
爸
Da!
约翰·罗斯
John Ross!
罗塞·罗斯 约翰·罗斯 你们得离开这栋房子
Rose Ross! John Ross! You need to leave this house!
有人来杀你们了
There are men coming here to kill you!
罗塞
Rose.
别激动
Easy.
我不是敌人
I'm a friend.
射穿那栋房子
Kill that house!
我知道如何完成工作
I know how to do a job right.
有的 先生 没有 先生 我有三满袋[童谣]
Yes, sir, no, sir, three bags full of sh...
小鸟
Kotori.
直到文明到来
Until civilization arrives.
盐
小鸟
Kotori.
罗塞
Rose...
杰伊
Jay...
Jay.
傻小子
Silly boy.
转过来 罗塞
Turn around, rose.
结束了
It's over.
一点儿都不疼
Doesn't hurt.
杰伊
Jay.
他全心全意地爱着你
He loved you with all his heart.
他爱错人了
His heart was in the wrong place.
他是真心实意的
His spirit was true.
杰伊·卡文迪什教会我
There is more to life than survival.
除了生存 生活还有更多的意义
Jay cavendish taught me that.
我欠他一条命
I owe him my life.
一路向西
Ho for the west.